On Sunday morning, Mr. and Mrs. Arable and Fern were sitting at breakfast in the kitchen.
Avery had finished and was upstairs looking for his slingshot. "Did you know
that Uncle Homer's goings had hatched?"
asked Fern. "How many?" asked Mr.
Arable. "Seven," replied Fern. "There were eight eggs, but one egg didn't
hatch, and the goose told Templeton she didn't want it anymore, so he took it away."
"The goose did what?" asked Mrs.
terrible, gazing at her daughter with a queer, worried look, "Told Templeton she
didn't want the egg anymore," repeated Fern. "Who is Templeton?" asked Mrs.
Arable. "He's the rat," replied Fern.
"None of us like him much." "Who's us?"
asked Mr. Arable. "Oh, everybody in the barn cellar. Wilbur and the sheep and
the lambs and the goose and the gander and the gosslings and Charlotte and me.
Charlotte said Mrs. Arable. Who's Charlotte? She's Wilbur's best friend.
She's terribly clever.
What does she look like? asked Mrs.
Arable. Well, uh, said Fern thoughtfully. She has eight legs. All spiders do, I guess.
Charlotte is a spider?" asked Fern's mother. Fern nodded. "A big gray one.
She has a web across the top of Wilbur's doorway. She catches flies and sucks
their blood. Wilbur adores her."
"Does he really?" said Mrs. Arable rather vaguely. She was staring at Fern
with a worried expression on her face.
Oh yes, Wilbur adores Charlotte, said Fern. Do you know what Charlotte said
when the gosslings hatched? I haven't the faintest idea, said Mr. Arable. Tell
us. Well, when the first go stuck its little head out from under the goose, I
was sitting on my stool in the corner and Charlotte was on her web. She made a speech.
She said, "I am sure that every one of us here in the barn seller will be
gratified to learn that after four weeks of unremittent effort and patience on
the part of the goose, she now has something to show for it." "Don't you
think that was a pleasant thing for her to say?" "Yes, I do," said Mrs. Arable.
"And now, Fern, it's time to get ready for Sunday school. and tell Avery to get ready.
And this afternoon, you can tell me more about what goes on in Uncle Homer's
barn. Aren't you spending quite a lot of time there? You go there almost every
afternoon, don't you? I like it there, replied Fern. She wiped her mouth and
ran upstairs. After she had left the room, Mrs. Arable spoke in a low voice
to her husband. I worry about Fern, she said. Did you hear the way she rambled
on about the animals, pretending that they talked?
Mr. Arable chuckled.
"Maybe they do talk," he said. "I've sometimes wondered. At any rate, don't
worry about Fern. She's just got a lively imagination. Kids think they hear
all sorts of things." Just the same, I do worry about her, replied Mrs. Arable.
I think I shall ask Dr. Doriap about her the next time I see him. He loves Fern
almost as much as we do, and I want him to know how queerly she's acting about
that pig and everything. I don't think it's normal. You know perfectly well
animals don't talk. Mr. Arable grinned.
Maybe our ears aren't as sharp as ferns, he said.
Chapter nine.
Wilbur's boast.